<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.MarcelineVPQ.Sonata</id>

  <name>Sonata</name>
  <summary>Desktop player for the Apple Music web app</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>

  <developer id="io.github.marcelinevpq">
    <name>MarcelineVPQ</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>
      Sonata is an unofficial desktop player for the Apple Music web app, with
      full DRM playback support via Widevine. Not affiliated with, endorsed by,
      or sponsored by Apple Inc.; "Apple Music" is a trademark of Apple Inc.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>System tray with playback controls</li>
      <li>Floating mini player with album art, progress bar, and volume</li>
      <li>Time-synced lyrics in a separate window</li>
      <li>Dark mode that follows your desktop theme</li>
      <li>Last.fm scrobbling and Discord Rich Presence</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.MarcelineVPQ.Sonata.desktop</launchable>

  <categories>
    <category>Audio</category>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
  </categories>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/MarcelineVPQ/apple-music-for-linux</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/MarcelineVPQ/apple-music-for-linux/issues</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>The mini player and time-synced lyrics window</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MarcelineVPQ/apple-music-for-linux/master/screenshots/lyrics-mini-player.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.15.6" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>Each window (main, mini player, lyrics) now remembers its own position separately on KDE Wayland, via KWin scripting — reliably, where the previous rule-based approach failed for the main window.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.15.5" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>Update restart now reliably relaunches into the new version by starting it in a clean session environment (the inherited environment was crashing the new instance).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.15.4" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>On KDE Wayland, window positions are now remembered across sessions (via a KWin rule) — the one thing Wayland won't let an app do on its own.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.15.3" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>"Restart Now" after an update now reliably relaunches into the new version, waiting for the old instance to fully exit and falling back to extract-and-run if needed.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.15.2" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>The app-menu entry now uses a stable symlink so it never breaks after an update. The mini player's Always on Top toggle also pins the lyrics window.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.15.1" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>Fixed a crash during self-update: the updater no longer deletes the running AppImage (which caused a SIGBUS); old versions are pruned safely on the next launch.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.15.0" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>Adaptive album color — the mini player and lyrics window retint to the current album art. The lyrics window now stays on top on KDE Wayland.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.14.3" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>Updates install under the new version's file name and restart cleanly, without crashing the replaced instance.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.14.2" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>The settings window shows the app version.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.14.1" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>Only one copy of the app runs at a time — launching it again surfaces the running window instead of opening another instance.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.14.0" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>The AppImage now installs itself into the app menu on first run and keeps itself up to date: new releases are downloaded and verified in the background, with a notification to restart into the new version.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.13.0" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>Tray icon tooltip shows the current track and artist; the mini player gained an Always on Top toggle in its ⋯ menu, working on KDE Wayland via KWin.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.12.0" date="2026-07-01">
      <description>
        <p>Track-change notifications, a settings window, launch-at-login and close-to-tray, remembered window sizes, and a refined Nebula visualizer.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.11.0" date="2026-07-01">
      <description>
        <p>Audio-reactive visualizer with four scenes (Bars, Aurora, Nebula, Toast) and synced lyrics.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.2" date="2026-07-01">
      <description>
        <p>Packaging and runtime updates.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.1" date="2026-07-01">
      <description>
        <p>Packaging: AUR package; store screenshot and metadata.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.0" date="2026-07-01">
      <description>
        <p>Rebranded to Sonata with a new icon. Mini player favorites, explicit badge, and hover times.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.1" date="2026-07-01">
      <description>
        <p>Security hardening.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.0" date="2026-07-01">
      <description>
        <p>Mini player, synced lyrics window, Discord Rich Presence, and Last.fm scrobbling.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
